In this chapter, we will learn the basic production process of CLO core tools and clothing.
First is the arrangement of core tools.
Open the library.
Select Connect.
Select CLO Training here in the Connect official account.
Then enter the core tool to search.
Press Return.
Select Core Tools Automatic Arrangement.
Double-click to open.
Then close the library.
The current version is already in 2D.
The window is arranged.
Now we need to arrange this T-shirt version to the model.
Here we can use the Automatic 3D Arrangement tool.
Click Run.
The Automatic Arrangement tool will automatically arrange its position based on the form of the version.
Select Confirm.
You can see that the current version is automatically arranged in the model.
select Confirm. You can see that the current version is automatically arranged in the model.
This is the automatic arrangement.
Of course, in addition to this, we can also use the manual arrangement panel to adjust the corresponding position on the model.
Open the library.
Select the core tool, Arrangements.
Double-click to open.
Select Confirm.
We open a new project file.
Close the library.
We can use the virtual model information display to display the arrangement points to open the arrangement points on the model.
At this time, you can see that there are many blue points around the model.
There are two arrangement points here.
The center axis is a pure blue point.
It is an asymmetric arrangement point.
There is a white circle outside the point on both sides.
It means that it is an symmetrical arrangement point.
Next, we arrange the panels.
Left-click to select the panel.
Then put the mouse on the model's arrangement point.
You can see that there is a gray preview at this time.
We can put it on different points.
Preview the arrangement position of the current panel.
We choose the arrangement point on the center axis.
Then left-click to set the arrangement point.
The panel is arranged in the corresponding position on the model.
Next, arrange the back of the model's clothing.
We can press the arrow on the keyboard to switch to the back view.
Select the back of the clothing.
Arrange its position.
Since the back of the clothing is symmetrical,
One side is arranged,
The other side is also arranged.
And the panel is facing the front and facing the back.
Back to the front view.
Arrange the belt panels.
And the eight on the keyboard in the reverse view.
Arrange the belt panels on the back.
After arranging,
See the attribute editor on the right side.
Slide the wheel to the bottom to see the arrangement.
We can adjust the arrangement of the parameters here.
To adjust the position of the belt panels on the back.
First of all, you can see.
When adjusting the position of the X-axis parameters.
The panel is rotating around the model's body level.
When we adjust the position of the Y-axis parameters.
The panel is moving vertically on the model's body.
Entering the value can also adjust the position of the panel.
The Y-axis refers to the distance between the panel and the model's body.
Adjusting parameters can see the changes in the arrangement of the panel position.
Switch to the view to check.
The direction can change the direction of the panel.
When adjusting the direction of the parameters.
The direction of the entire panel is also changing.
We can adjust these parameters.
To adjust through the arrangement point.
Arrange the position of the panel on the model.
Then press the 2 on the keyboard.
Back to the front view.
Next, arrange the panel of the skirt.
Here.
We can arrange the skirt in the model.
The position of the front, middle and bottom.
After arranging.
You can use the positioning ball to adjust its position.
Left click to press the green arrow.
Slightly move down.
In this way, the front skirt is arranged.
Then select the skirt at the back.
Press 8 to the rear view.
Arrange the skirt at the back.
At the same time, you can use the positioning ball.
Press the green arrow.
Slightly move it down.
You can also use the blue arrow.
Pull it a little forward.
So we have completed the arrangement of the clothing parts.
The clothes are ready.